<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Music on Neoneu</title>
        <link>https://neoneu.github.io/tags/music/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Music on Neoneu</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Neoneu</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neoneu.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Waltz of the Flowers</title>
        <link>https://neoneu.github.io/p/waltz-of-the-flowers/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://neoneu.github.io/p/waltz-of-the-flowers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://neoneu.github.io/p/waltz-of-the-flowers/valse.png" alt="Featured image of post Waltz of the Flowers" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s awfully fun to write a march for tin soldiers, and a waltz for flowers!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Edwardian Script ITC&#34;&gt;Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tchaikovsky’s iconic &lt;em&gt;Waltz of the Flowers&lt;/em&gt; is a piece of orchestral music that features in the second act of his ever-loved festive ballet &lt;em&gt;The Nutcracker&lt;/em&gt;. The ballet was premiered at Christmastime in 1892, and has since been one of the most popular ballets in the world. It is based on E. T. A Hoffmann’s 1816 fairytale &lt;em&gt;The Nutcracker&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Mouse King&lt;/em&gt;, which tells the story of a young girl who adventures into the ‘Land of Sweets’ on Christmas Eve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, it is a challenge to play such a piece of orchestral music on a single guitar, since some details will inevitably be lost. However, I just love this piece so much that I can&amp;rsquo;t help myself trying to figure out the whole piece on my own guitar. Fortunately, I finally created its guitar tablature. All work is done on the Power TAB Editor. If you also want to compose you own work, just do it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;Waltz%20of%20the%20Flowers.pdf&#34; &gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the pdf of the TAB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;Waltz%20of%20the%20Flowers.pt2&#34; &gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the pt2 file of the TAB, in which you can play and edit the TAB if you have already installed Power TAB Editor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
